

i Australian Citizen
t-61 450 988 769
haolin@haolin.dev

www.haolin.devgithub.com/DragoniteHaolin

HAOLIN WU

I am a Software Engineer with four years of industry experience developing in professional environments. During that time, I have handled entire software life-cycles including analysis, testing and DevOps, whilst working in teams both as a developer and project manager. My work has impacted hundreds of thousands of customers, and given me a customer-first mindset during the entire DevOps lifecycle.

With a double major degree in both computer science and data science, I am also well versed and have practical experience in web development, data integration, data visualization, data mining, high performance computing, and machine learning (incl. deep learning).

I am hard working, pay attention to detail, work well in teams, and manage my time well to meet deadlines.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021 Bachelor of Science (Honours)

The University of Western Australia

Honours in Computer Science and Data Science

Research Topic: Deep Learning for Information Extraction from PDF Tables

First Class Honours, 6.375 GPA

2016 - 2019 Bachelor of Science (Double Major)

The University of Western Australia

Degree Specific Major: Computer Science

Second Major: Data Science

EXPERIENCE

2022 - current **Software Engineer**

Telstra

Developed and maintained various components across Telstra.com for Telstra Digital. Lead the development in Telstra Outages, a tool used by hundreds of thousands of customers to visualize network outages and outage areas. Developed using a variety of modern practices such as Test Driven Development (TDD), continuous integration and frameworks. Additionally, added logging and monitoring for traffic and statistics through Splunk and New Relic.

TypeScript / React / Spring / New Relic / AEM / Splunk / Java

2021 - 2022 Software Engineer

FairSupply Analytics Pty Ltd.

Developed a REST API using Django Rest Framework to replace an existing NoSQL database to improve referential integrity and scalability. The API integration was implemented within a legacy AngularJS application, and then containerized using Docker, with continuous integration through GitHub Actions. A Secure Development Lifecycle (SDLC) was used, along with Test Driven Development (TDD) approaches. The application was then deployed using AWS.

Django Rest Framework / Docker / Python / TDD / CI/CD / SDLC / AngularJS

2020 - 2021 **Q**

Casual Academic

The University of Western Australia

Casual Academic for CITS3403 Agile Web Development and CITS3004 Cybersecurity. Teaching agile methodologies, Python3 web frameworks, and continuous integration and deployment techniques. Additionally teaching containerization through Docker, web vulnerabilities, white hat hacking, and cyber-attack prevention.

Python / Flask / Docker / Git / JS / PostgreSQL / CTFs

2019 – 2021 Full Stack Engineer

The Raine Study / UWA Centre for Software and Security Practice

Project management system developed for the Raine Study, a scientific study collecting data over 30 years from a cohort of participants. I used agile methodologies with Python/Django back-end and JQuery front-end technologies, while deploying to AWS services such as EC2, RDS, and S3.

Python / Django / Bootstrap / Git / JS / AWS

2018 – 2019 Front-End Developer

Corporate Governance Risk Pty Ltd

User interface and user experience (UI/UX) development of software for BHP, PwC, and other

companies using Ruby and React.

JS / Bootstrap / Redux / React / CSS / JSX

2017 – 2018 Software Intern

UWA Centre for Software and Security Practice

Full stack development of a variety of small apps for clients of UWA CSSP.

Python / Django / HTML / CSS

ACHIEVEMENTS

2020 Teaching Commendation

The University of Western Australia

For outstanding teaching in CITS3403, Agile Web Development

2018 Unearthed Hackathon Young Innovator Winner

Unearthed Solutions, Perth

Sponsored by BHP and Amazon AWS

2010-2014 Scotch College Dual Scholarship Recipient

Scotch College, Perth

Dual Scholarship Recipient in both Academics and Music

HIGHLIGHTS

Startup Archee - Agile Toolkit

Working in agile teams, often planning tools online were pay-walled or had very poor user experience. To overcome these issues, I built a solution to the popular agile planning strategy Planning Poker, and then decided to extend this to building an agile toolkit. This became Archee, and is an extendible to the popular agile toolkit.

application we manage free of charge for hundreds of users every month.

NextJS / React / TypeScript / Vercel / AWS / Websockets / PlanetScale

Research Deep Learning for Information Extraction from PDF Tables

Honours research project exploring deep learning methods for extracting tabular semantics from tables inside PDFs into a machine readable format using **TensorFlow** and **PyTorch**. Allows for older PDF documents and forms such as maintenance procedures and medical discharge letters independent of domain to be stored as JSON and standardised. The project surveys, implements, and integrates Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing techniques for table extraction

and semantic relation identification.

Project Various Projects

Some projects completed over the years include machine learning web applications, customer transaction applications, and webhook cronjob integrations. These projects are often developed using Test Driven Development (TDD), Continuous Integration and Deployment (CI/CD), and DevOps principles. These projects can be viewed in detail within my portfolio.

https://www.haolin.dev

Feature

REFERENCES

Alvin Chong

+61 383 877 403

Team Lead at Telstra

Software

Professor Melinda Hodkiewicz

BHP Billiton Fellow, School of Engineering, The University of Western

Australia +61 8 6488 7911

alvin.c.chong@team.telstra.com melinda.hodkiewicz@uwa.edu.au

Dr. David Glance

Information Security Consultant

Engineering

+61 408 916 579

david.glance@gmail.com

Senior Lecturer at The University of Western Australia

+61 8 6488 2794

Dr. Tim French

tim.french@uwa.edu.au

LANGUAGES

English - native Chinese Mandarin - fluent

HOBBIES

Coding is an art to me. In my spare time I enjoy automating tasks in my day to day life, such as smart home integration and some custom Fintech. I also love playing piano, acrylic painting, swimming, and fishing.

NON PROFIT

I created **Archee**, an agile toolkit to help planning sprints, after identifying the need of a planning tool in my team. I created software to manage the **UWA Ethical Hacking Club**, allowing weekly events and notifications. Additionally I taught English to international students at **Melbourne University**.